<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Core changes</title>
    <author email="tryggvi@idega.com">Tryggvi Larusson</author>
  </properties>
  <body>

	<release version="3.1.25" date="2007-01-22">
		<action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
			Moved security filter for Web-Services, WebServiceAuthorizationFilter, from the block com.idega.block.process.webservice to
			be standard part of com.idega.core.
		</action>
		<action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
			Updated JAAS LoginModule implementation and added a standard PersonalIdCredential object that is always initialized for
			all users that login-in and have a personalId set. This was updated because of requirements from VUF - Reykjavik.
		</action>
	</release>
  
	<release version="3.1.24" date="2007-01-05">
		<action dev="laddi" type="update">
			Changed DayOfWeekAndDate so that it doesn't display the day of week twice for locales other than Icelandic.
		</action>
		<action dev="laddi" type="update">
			Added locale as style class for all widgets.
		</action>
	</release>
    
	<release version="3.1.23" date="2006-12-13">
		<action dev="laddi" type="update">
			Fixed implementation of compareTo(IDOEntity) in GenericEntity so that it doesn't throw a ClassCastException when primary key is not a String.
		</action>
	</release>
    
	<release version="3.1.22" date="2006-11-23">
		<action dev="laddi" type="update">
			Changed print implementation in Page to accomodate for different types of bundle style sheets.
		</action>
	</release>
    
	<release version="3.1.21" date="2006-11-20">
		<action dev="palli" type="update">
			Added a reply to parameter to the send methods in SendMail.
		</action>
		<action dev="eiki" type="update">
			Changed all timed threads I found to daemon threads to ensure that they can be killed on a shutdown. 
			Classes changed: IBOTimedServiceBean, EventTimer,ConnectionRefresher and TimerManager.
		</action>
	</release>
    
	<release version="3.1.20" date="2006-11-15">
		<action dev="laddi" type="fix">
			Fixed loading layer so that it displays correctly cross-browser.
		</action>
	</release>

	<release version="3.1.19" date="2006-11-09">
		<action dev="gimmi" type="update">
			SearchResults can now be set to open links in a new window
		</action>
	</release>

	<release version="3.1.18" date="2006-11-09">
		<action dev="laddi" type="update">
			Added displaying of Loading Layer on click when using Link to submit Form.
		</action>
	</release>

   	<release version="3.1.17" date="2006-11-06">
		<action dev="gimmi" type="update">
			Small update to SearchResults, making is more flexible to being extended
		</action>
	</release>
	   	<release version="3.1.16" date="2006-11-02">
		<action dev="laddi" type="fix">
			Fixed incorrect cache handling of application bindings with keys larger than max value.
		</action>
		<action dev="laddi" type="update">
			Added possibility to include style sheets with specific media type through GlobalIncludeManager.
		</action>
	</release>
   
   	<release version="3.1.15" date="2006-10-25">
		<action dev="gimmi" type="fix">
			Added saveState and restoreState to Link.
		</action>
	</release>
   
  	<release version="3.1.14" date="2006-10-24">
		<action dev="gimmi" type="add">
			added a method for getting extra row elements for the search result.
		</action>
	</release>
  
	<release version="3.1.13" date="2006-10-19">
		<action dev="laddi" type="update">
		Fixed getting reflection properties for rebuilding the blocks.
		</action>
	</release>

	<release version="3.1.12" date="2006-10-04">
		<action dev="laddi" type="update">
			Changed so that when using Link to submit a Form it is impossible to double click (only works when using setToFormSubmit method).
		</action>
	</release>

	<release version="3.1.11" date="2006-09-20">
		<action dev="gimmi" type="fix">
			Added an addTrigger to ResultOutput
		</action>
	</release>

	<release version="3.1.10" date="2006-09-07">
		<action dev="gimmi" type="fix">
			Some major fixes in InterfaceObject regarding setting object values onclick... keep your eyes open.
		</action>
	</release>

	<release version="3.1.9" date="2006-09-07">
		<action dev="gimmi" type="fix">
			Fixed for and InterfaceObject to allow for 2 forms in the same page with different form input checks.
		</action>
	</release>

	<release version="3.1.8" date="2006-08-01">
		<action dev="gimmi" type="add">
			New class, PageInfoWriter prints page info into the out log
		</action>
	</release>

	<release version="3.1.7" date="2006-08-01">
		<action dev="gimmi" type="add">
			Added some getPublicWindow methods to Window and GenericButton
		</action>
	</release>

	<release version="3.1.6" date="2006-07-27">
		<action dev="laddi" type="fix">
			Changed pop up window in Help to public window.
		</action>
	</release>
  
	<release version="3.1.5" date="2006-07-20">
		<action dev="gimmi" type="fix">
			Reimplemented exporting pages
		</action>
	</release>
  
  	<release version="3.1.4" date="2006-07-07">
     <action dev="eiki" type="add">
      Added new class, SearchResultComparator, a comparator that can sort by any property in SearchResult and its attribute map properties (String,Number and Date).
     </action>
      <action dev="eiki" type="fix">
      	SearchResults , bugfix uses toString now instead of requiring searchresult attributes to be strings
		</action>
    </release>
    
   <release version="3.1.3" date="2006-07-06">
      <action dev="eiki" type="fix">
      	Fixes and addons for SearchResults so you can show or hide extra search result parameters.
      </action>
    </release>
    
   <release version="3.1.2" date="2006-07-03">
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="fix">
        	Fixed and addons for SmallCalendar (HTML, setting class and dateParameterName)
      </action>
    </release>
  
  
   <release version="3.1.1" date="2006-06-30">
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="fix">
      	Fix for HSQLDB database where front page with ib_page_id=0 was causing a permission bug (not displayed).
      </action>
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="fix">
     	Bugfix for NullpointerException caused in ICObjectBMPBean where objectType or bundle was null. (Travel)
      </action>
      <action dev="eiki" type="update">
      	Refactored and improved SearchResult to be more extendable. See new module WhatIsNew in the com.idega.content bundle for an example.
      </action>
    </release>
      
    <release version="3.1.0" date="2006-06-16">
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
      	 New Cache sub-system. IWCacheManager2, which builds on the Open source ehCache project.
      </action>
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
      	Caching support for rendered content general general JSF UIComponents (Content Caching). Builds on the IWCacheManager2.
      </action>
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
     	 IDO Persistence framework updates. Updates to facilitate usage of caching of entity beans
     	 and better control of pre-loading large collection of beans from finder methods.
      </action>
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
      	Performance optimizations and caching implemented for beans ICObject,ICObjectInstance,ICLocale
      </action>
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
      	Added experimental support for the H2 (http://www.h2database.com/) database engine.
      </action>
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
      	New ComponentRegstry object which manages all available components to the system. Addition of
      	a reader for faces-config.xml documents embedded into the jar files of installed modules to read all
      	JSF components registered into these descriptors into the ComponentRegistry.
      </action>
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
      	Misc. updates to unify look-and-feel of UI components (IWAdminWindow) and adjusting to newer ePlatform look.
      </action>
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
      	Better Unit test support. Base classes to develop JUnit tests for idegaWeb applications.
      	Simple Application unit test now included in the com.idega.core module which is integrated 
      	into the maven build lifecycle.
      </action>
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
      	Adding inclusion of LogDriver standard with the system.
      </action>
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
      	Locale variants now supported, which can be used to implement customer specific localizations.
      </action>
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
      	Update to the most recent myfaces 1.1.3 release.
      </action>
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="fix">
      	Misc. other small bugfixes.
      </action>
    </release>
  
    <release version="3.0.6" date="2005-09-15">
      <action dev="thomas" type="update">
      	This version is used for the ePlatform 3.0.
      </action>              
    </release>
    
    <release version="3.0.5" date="2005-05-24">
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
      	This version is used for the nacka 24 app.
      </action>              
    </release>
    
    <release version="3.0.4" date="2005-04-06">
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
      	This version is the very first one with a correct iwbar.
        Declaration of version for use in new systems based on JSF.
      </action>              
    </release>
    
    <release version="3.0.0" date="2005-03-10">
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
        Declaration of version for use in new systems based on JSF.
      </action>              
    </release>

    <release version="2.0.0" date="2005-01-13">
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
        Declaration of version for use in old style systems before a 3.0 release is declared.
      </action>              
    </release>

    <release version="1.9" date="2004-09-07">
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="update">
        Declaring a 1.9 version before much of the maven refactoring is done.
      </action>
      <!--     
      <action dev="tryggvil" type="fix" issue="JIRA-XXX">
        Corrected bug blah blah.
      </action>              
      <action dev="vmassol" type="remove" due-to="John Doe" due-to-email="john@doe.com">
        Removed blah blah.
      </action>
      -->
    </release>
  </body>
</document>
